imeche.org 2015-12-19

# Privacy policy and disclaimer - Institution of Mechanical Engineers

## Important information when visiting the IMechE website

Please read the following terms and conditions. By using this website ("Website") you are taken to have read, understood and consented to these terms and conditions ("Terms"). Please ask if you are uncertain about these terms and conditions.

## About IMechE

This Website is operated by the Institution of Mechanical Engineers ("IMechE") of 1 Birdcage Walk, London, SW1H 9JJ. 

For the purposes of any personal data processed whilst you visit this website, the Data Controller will be the IMechE. The IMechE is registered with the UK Information Commissioner, a copy of the registration is available via the Information Commissioner website at www.ico.gov.uk.

## Privacy

IMechE will process your personal data including; your contact details, areas of engineering interest, details of academic record and employment experience or history, order and delivery data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (“Act”).

### Use of Your Personal Data

IMechE may use your personal data in the following ways:

  * to process membership applications and renewals and for all other membership administration; 
  * to provide you with beneficial information, products or services that either you request or which IMechE believes may benefit you. To amend your marketing preferences please see the section ‘Your Rights’, below.
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and IMechE; and 
  * to notify you about changes to IMechE services. 

IMechE collects information about users of the Website for two main reasons:

  * to help the IMechE improve the Website and the services the IMechE offers; and
  * to obtain aggregate statistics to help the IMechE achieve its constitutional purposes.

The IMechE will respect your e-mail privacy, and will only send you unsolicited mail if you have agreed to this. The IMechE will not pass on your e-mail address and contact details unless the IMechE has your prior consent. Please note that telephone calls to the IMechE may be monitored or recorded.

### Contacting you for marketing purposes

The IMechE will only use your information for marketing purposes, or to promote new services, activities or online content where you have agreed to this.

### Disclosure of your information

IMechE may permit selected third parties to use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which will be beneficial to you. If at any time you do not wish your contact details to be shared for marketing purposes, you can simply let us know using the contact details in the ‘Your Rights’ section below.

Delegates at IMechE Events have told us it is beneficial to see who else is attending an event. For this reason we make available a list of all delegates (name and job title) to those who are themselves attending an event (the ‘Delegate List’). Should you not wish to appear on this list, please contact us **prior to the event** by emailing events@imeche.org.

IMechE will only disclose your personal information to third parties without your consent if it is;

  * under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or
  * in order to enforce or apply the terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of IMechE, its members or others. 
  * for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

IMechE may disclose your personal information to any of its wholly owned subsidiaries.

## Your rights

### Your right to prevent marketing

IMechE will always actively seek your consent for marketing purposes. You always have the right to change your preferences and ask IMechE not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. IMechE will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if it intends to use your data for such purposes or if it intends to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. 

You can exercise the right at any time by (1) visiting the [preferences section of your online account](https://www.imeche.org/my-account/ProfileMailingPref) (3) writing to IMechE at 1 Birdcage Walk, London SW1H 9JJ or (4) sending an email to [enquiries@imeche.org](mailto:enquiries@imeche.org).

### Your right to access your information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act by writing to the Data Protection Officer at IMechE, 1 Birdcage Walk, London SW1H 9JJ or digital@imeche.org. 

Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet IMechE costs in providing you with details of the information held about you.

## IP Addresses and cookies

The IMechE may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type and for system administration. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual. This data is primarily used for;

  * helping the IMechE improve the Website and the services the IMechE offers;
  * providing statistics to help the IMechE achieve its constitutional purposes;
  * an estimation of audience size and usage patterns; 
  * to store preferences information to allow for Website customising, and;
  * to recognise members’ log in details for return visits to the IMechE Website. 

For statistical reasons, the IMechE may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help the IMechE to improve this site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, the Website will issue cookies when you log on to it. Data security

Your data may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. IMechE will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where IMechE has given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. IMechE request that you do not share a password with anyone.

The transmission of information via the internet is not always secure. IMechE will protect your personal data in accordance with current best practice but, it cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once IMechE has received your information, it will use procedures and security features to minimise the likelihood of unauthorised access.

## Third party websites

This Website contains links to other websites. These websites are not operated by the IMechE and are outside the control of the IMechE. The IMechE accepts no responsibility whatsoever for these websites or their contents. In particular, if you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that IMechE does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites

## Use of material

The Contents of this website are for general information only. The contents are not intended to address specific requirements or form specific advice. The IMechE gives no warranty as to the accuracy, completeness or fitness for purpose of the Contents or for keeping the Contents up-to-date and accepts no liability resulting from your use of the Contents.

## Copyright

Unless stated otherwise, copyright and other intellectual property rights in the contents ("Contents") of this Website are owned by, or licensed to, the IMechE. You may only print (or download to disk) the Contents for the purpose of private and personal non-commercial use, and may not otherwise copy, reproduce, distribute, republish, download, display, post or transmit, in any form whatsoever, or by any means, the contents without the express permission of the IMechE (Please see "Further Inquiry").

## Exclusion of liability

The IMechE does not accept liability of any description, including liability for negligence (except for personal injury or death), or any damages or losses (including, but not limited to, indirect or consequential loss, or loss of business, revenue, profits, use or opportunity) howsoever arising from your use (or inability to use) this Website or the Contents.

## Governing law

This website and these Terms are governed exclusively by English law and are subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England and Wales. 

## Revision

The IMechE reserves the right to revise and update the Terms from time to time, so you may wish to check it each time you submit personal information to the IMechE. If you do not agree to these changes, please do not continue to use IMechE websites to submit personal information to the IMechE. 

## Further inquiry

If you any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact:

The Data Protection Officer  
1 Birdcage Walk  
London  
SW1H 9JJ

(Email: digital@imeche.org )

The IMechE is a registered charity no. 206882.
